esds.co.in 2014-08-20

# ESDS Software Solution Data Privacy Policy

## ESDS Data Privacy Policy

We at ESDS, value and respect privacy of the data that our clients / prospects / visitors provide us during each interaction. The purpose of our Privacy Policy is to demonstrate our firm's extreme commitment to the privacy and protection of data of all the persons who provide personal data to ESDS. Our Data Privacy Policy elucidates the manner in which we collect information from and about you, and what we do with the information, so that you may opt for whether or not to provide personal information to us.

By visiting ESDS® websites or otherwise providing your personal information to ESDS via any other means, you accept and consent to the terms & conditions of this Data Privacy Policy.

For purposes of this policy, the term "visitor" includes visitors to our website who are not yet our customers and those who eventually become our customers i.e. whether you upload information to our website, download it, or are merely visiting our website. While visiting our website you may choose not to divulge certain information but then you may be devoid of taking advantage of many of its features.

**1\. WHAT DATA DO WE COLLECT AND FROM WHERE?**

The personal information we collect may include: Visitors name, contact information, financial information and payment card details, IP addresses, Live chat messages, Telephone conversations, product and service selections and orders or other things that may be used for visitor identification. Generally, we may collect personal information in the following manner:

  * __The Visitor may provide his/her personal information to us via live chat, email or other written correspondence, telephone calls, web based forms, or any other similar means
  * __We use automated technical means to collect personal information about our website visitors for example – by use of cookies
  * __Purchases of services on our website; and
  * __Via third party providers.

**Web Visits**

You may visit our Website in any of the following ways:

  * __By using your browser to navigate to www.esds.co.in; or
  * __By viewing an advertisement displayed on a third party website that has content served by our web server.
  * __By viewing an email that is served content by our web server;

Whenever any visitor browse our website, our server logs the visitors IP address (unique network addresses), the time and duration of the visit, and the time and duration of the pages viewed on our website. If the visitor arrives at our website by clicking a paid advertisement (including a paid search engine result) or a link in an email, then we will capture information that tracks visit from that particular link. If the visitor arrives at our website by clicking a non-paid source, such as link in a non-paid search engine result or an unsponsored link on another website, we may capture information that tracks visit from that source; to the extent we are able to do so. We may also capture information about the visitor's computer system, such as browser type and operating system.

We are likely place a cookie on visitor's hard drive during the web visit. A cookie is a unique alphanumeric identifier that we use to help us identify the number of unique visitors to our website, whether or not those visitors are repeat visitors, and the source of their visits. Cookies cannot be executed as a code or used to deliver a virus, other servers cannot read them and personal information cannot be gathered from them. They are simply an identifier shared between the visitor and us to allow us to improve the services we offer to through our website.

We do not collect personal information about the visitor as part of a web visit, but web visit information may be tied to other information (including personal information) we collect from you via chat, web forms, and the other means as described in this Data Privacy Policy.

We may provide links to third-party websites for the visitor's convenience and information only with visitors prior consent. The data privacy practices of those sites may differ from ESDS practices and are not controlled by ESDS and are not covered by this Privacy Statement. We do not make any representations about third-party websites. We recommend all our visitor's to review their Data Privacy Policies before submitting their personal data.

**Sensitive Information**

We will not intentionally collect or maintain, and do not want you to provide, any information regarding your medical or health condition, race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs or other sensitive information.

**Children's Online Privacy Protection**

Our services are directed towards users in their business capacity and are not designed for or directed to children under the age of 18, and we will not intentionally collect or maintain information about anyone under the age of 18.

**2\. WHAT DO WE USE THIS INFORMATION FOR?**

**Personal Information**

We may use visitor's personal information to process service requests, handle orders, deliver products and services, process payments (and for visitor's safety, this includes verifying credit card details and fraud screening checks), communicate with the visitor about their orders, provide access to secure areas of the website, recommend merchandise and services that might be of interest to the visitor, to personalize visitor's visit to our website, and to enable us to review, develop and continually improve the products services and offers we provide online. We also use this information to prevent or detect fraud or any kind of abuses of our website and to enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

**Contact Information**

We use visitor information to send news / updates about our company to visitors and to get in touch with them when necessary. We also use the information we collect to improve the content of our websites and as training aides for our employees. Visitors are given the choice at the point when we request their information.

**Financial Information and payment card details**

We may ask visitors to enter credit card or account information in order to process orders for services placed with ESDS. Financial information provided via our website or via the client portal is encrypted for its protection prior to its transmission over the internet. We collect this information on a transaction-by- transaction basis and will not authorize the release of the information with anyone not directly involved in processing the transaction or fraud screening. This information may be encrypted and stored for logging purposes in accordance with applicable regulatory requirements.

Credit card numbers are used only for processing payments and are not used for any other purposes. When we use third party service providers for credit card processing services and fraud screening, we will enter into a written agreement with such third party ensuring appropriate security and confidentiality measures are in place to safeguard visitors personal data.

We use web visit information to measure interest in and develop our web pages and marketing plans, customize the content you view on your web visits based on your activity on past visits, and administer our website.

We use the visitors' IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers, and to administer our website.

We use cookies to help us recognize visitors as unique visitors (just a number) when they return to our websites For example, if there are 1,000 visits to our website on a certain day, we can use cookies to discover how many of those visits were made via the same browser (same visitor). We may also use the cookie to discover whether a certain visitor has visited our site more than once, and the source for each visit. We also use cookies to:

  * __allow us to tailor content or advertisements to match visitors preferred interest;
  * __avoid showing visitors the same advertisements repeatedly;
  * __compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our site;
  * __to help us improve the structure of our website (we cannot identify visitors personally in this way);
  * __count the number of anonymous users of our sites.

We use visitor's information provided to us via chat, email, web forms and other communications to correspond with the visitor about services they may be interested in purchasing. If the visitor select to purchase a service online using a web form, we will use the information to establish their account and for quality assurance purposes. Information submitted by the visitor in writing, such as chat, email, and web form information is archived and may be tied to information that we collect about visitor's web visits. Unless the visitor expressly mentions that a telephone call should be recorded, we do not record telephone conversations, but we may enter information provided by the visitor via telephone into our systems for the aforesaid usage.

**3\. DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

**Disclosure to Third Parties**

Personal information we gather is for internal use only and will not authorize the release of this information to anyone outside ESDS (save for third party service providers to ESDS who perform functions on our behalf but in such event personal information will only be shared to the extent reasonably necessary to perform their functions and they will not be authorized to use it for any other function), unless you have consented to such disclosure. 

If the visitor breaches our terms and conditions or website terms, or if we are under a duty to disclose or share the visitor's personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, we may disclose your information only to a relevant authority. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. In particular, we may release the information we collect to third parties when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law, to enforce our legal rights, to protect the rights and safety of others, or to assist with industry efforts to control fraud, spam or other undesirable conduct.

We may release the information we collect to third parties, where the information is provided to enable such third party to provide services to us, provided that the third party has agreed to use at least the same level of privacy protections described in this Privacy Policy, and is permitted to use the information only for the purpose of providing services to us.

If we wish to give your contact or personal information to a third party under any other circumstances, we will notify the visitor and give them a chance to opt out.

Any disclosure of personal information will be strictly be controlled and made fully in accordance with ISO 9001:2008 standards.

**4\. OPTING OUT OF COMMUNICATION**

The visitor may withdraw his/her consent to our use of their personal information for future marketing mailings, at any time by emailing us at an abuse@esds.co.in. For other ways to contact us please see our "Contact Us" page. We will use all reasonable endeavors to remove the visitor's personal information from our marketing mailing list within 5 business days of receipt of withdrawal of consent.

**5\. HOW SECURE IS THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT?**

ESDS is committed to industry best practices approaches concerning security measures to prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of the information in our possession. We use various security measures to protect the information we collect, as appropriate to the type of information, including encryption, firewalls, and access controls. Visitor's textual information is encrypted during transmission, our company databases are accessible only by persons who have entered into and are bound by a confidentiality and nondisclosure agreement with ESDS.

**6\. RIGHT TO ACCESS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

A Customer has the rights to access his/her individual information held by us. The visiting customer can obtain access to his/her personal information held by us through a written request in the form of an email to our billing team. If you have any questions about ESDS's Data Protection Policy please write to billing@esds.co.in

We always endeavor to make sure that the information we hold about the visitor is accurate and up to date, if the visitor is under the belief that any information we are holding about him/her is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us or e-mail us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

**7\. CHANGES**

Our business changes constantly and ISO 9001:2008 clauses may also change from time to time. The visitor should check our website frequently to see recent changes; however, we will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of personal information collected in the past without the visitor's prior consent. Unless stated otherwise, our current Data Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about the visitors.

This Data Privacy Policy was last updated on 7th November 2012.

**eNlight Cloud -** 99.99% Uptime // Free upgrade assistance // 24x7 Support // Plans from __499/month // Explore Now! __
